Guide to the Records of The New York Institute for the Humanities RG.37.4
New York University Archives
- Series III. Audio and Video Recordings, 1974-2010
  - Subseries IIIB. 1/4 Inch Reels, 1976-1991
    - Italo Calvino II, March 30, 1983; cuid4329; 1 sound tape reels 17:11; Container label (back): 3/30/83, L.S.C. E+L, New York University, 1 of 2, NY Institute for the Humanities.
      Tape 2 of 2 from this event. Tapes from this event are in Box 75, folders 16 & 17.
      Italo Calvino discusses writing (second tape of two from this event.).
      - Original Recording (Box 75, Quarter inch audio reel 16)
      - Access Copy (Box Shared University Archives 110, Cd 7:13)
    - "Jakobsen as Structural Linguist and Slavist" A Lecture by Edward Stankiewicz:, 28-Apr-1983; cuid4330 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Roland Barthes Festival: Richard Howard and Marshall Blonsky "A Conversation on Residual Barthes." Herbert Blau "Barthes and Beckett" The Pensum and Punctum" - Tape II, 19-May-83; cuid4331 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Roland Barthes Fesitval: Richard Howard and Marshall Blonsky "A Conversation on Residual Barthes." Herbert Blau "Barthes and Beckett" The Pensum and Punctum" Tape II, 19-May-83; cuid4332 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Roland Barthes Festival: Domna Stanton "The Mater of the Text" Philippe Roger "Portrait of the Artist as 'Gide mangeant une poire" Lawrence Kritzman "Barthesian Free Play" Tape I, 19-May-83; cuid4333 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Roland Barthes Festival: Domna Stanton "The Mater of the Text" Philippe Roger "Portrait of the Artist as 'Gide mangeant une poire" Lawrence Kritzman "Barthesian Free Play" Tape II, 19-May-83; cuid4334 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Auden Festival: Symposium on "Auden's Legacy" I, October 20, 1983; cuid4335; 1 sound tape reels; Container Label (front): Symposium on Auden's Legacy. Participants: Christopher Isherwood, J.D. CcClatchy, Dr. Ursula Niebuhr, Sir Stephen Spender, Edward Mendleson, moderator; Container label (back): Humanities, E+L Auditorium, 10/20/83, 7PM - 9PM, Reel 1 of 3.
      Participants include Christopher Isherwood, J.D. McClatchy, Dr. Ursula Niebuhr, Sir Stephen Spender, and Edward Mendleson as moderator.
      7 1/2 IPS; Last three minutes of tape are in reverse.
      Tape 1 of 3 from this event. Tapes for this event are in Box 75, Folders 24-26.
      Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986; Niebuhr, Ursula; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-2018; Mendelson, Edward
      - Original Recording (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 24)
      - Access Copies (Box Shared University Archives 110, Cd 7:15-7:16)
    - Auden Festival: Symposium on "Auden's Legacy" II, October 20, 1983; cuid4336; 1 sound tape reels; Container Label (front): Symposium on Auden's Legacy. Participants: Christopher Isherwood, J.D. CcClatchy, Dr. Ursula Niebuhr, Sir Stephen Spender, Edward Mendleson, moderator; Container label (back): Humanities, E+L Auditorium, 10/20/83, 7PM - 9PM, Reel 2 of 3.
      Tape 2 of 3 from this event.Tapes for this event are in Box 75, Folders 24-26.
      Mendelson, Edward; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-2018; Niebuhr, Ursula; Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986
      - Original Recording (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 25)
      - Access Copy (Box Shared University Archives 110, Cd 7:17)
    - Auden Festival: Symposium on "Auden's Legacy" III, October 20, 1983; cuid4337; 1 sound tape reels; Container Label (front): Symposium on Auden's Legacy. Participants: Christopher Isherwood, J.D. CcClatchy, Dr. Ursula Niebuhr, Sir Stephen Spender, Edward Mendleson, moderator; Container label (back): Humanities, E+L Auditorium, 10/20/83, 7PM - 9PM, Reel 3 of 3.
      Participants include Christopher Isherwood, J.D. McClatchy, Dr. Ursula Niebuhr, Sir Stephen Spender, and Edward Mendelson as moderator.
      Tape 3 of 3 from this event. Tapes for this event are in Box 75, Folders 24-26.
      Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986; Niebuhr, Ursula; Mendelson, Edward; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-2018; Spender, Stephen, 1909-1995
      - Original Recording (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 26)
      - Access Copy (Box Shared University Archives 110, Cd 7:18)
    - Roland Barthes Festival: "Barthes and the Visual Arts" Roundtable Discussion with Dore Ashton, Richard Avedon, Annette Michelson, Richard Sennett, Edmund White, Tape I, 18-May-84; cuid4338 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Roland Barthes Festival: "Barthes and the Visual Arts" Roundtable Discussion with Dore Ashton, Richard Avedon, Annette Michelson, Richard Sennett, Edmund White, Tape II, 19-May-84; cuid4339 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Breyten Breytenbach "The Writer in Totalitarian Countries" I, 6-Feb-85; cuid4340 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Breyten Breytenbach "The Writer in Totalitarian Countries" II, 6-Feb-85; cuid4341 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Breyten Breytenbach "The Writer in Totalitarian Countries" III, 6-Feb-85; cuid4342 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Times Square Conference I, 26-Oct-90; cuid4343 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Times Square Conference II, 26-10-90; cuid4344 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Times Square Conference III, 26-Oct-90; cuid4345 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Russian Cons Eve I, 21-Mar-91; cuid4346 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Russian Cons Eve II, 21-Mar-91; cuid4347 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - AM I, 21-Mar-91; cuid4348 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - AM II, 21-Mar-91; cuid4349 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - AM III, 21-Mar-91; cuid4350 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Glasnost PM I, 21-Mar-1991; cuid4351 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Glasnost PM II, 21-Mar-91; cuid4352 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Morning I, 22-Mar-91; cuid4353 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Morning II, 22-Mar-91; cuid4354 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - PM I, 22-Mar-91; cuid4355 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - PM II, 22-Mar-91; cuid4356 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Glasnost AM I, 22-Mar-91; cuid4357 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Glasnost Eve I, 22-Mar-91; cuid4358 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Glasnost AM II, 22-Mar-91; cuid4359 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Glasnost Eve II, 22-Mar-91; cuid4360 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Subseries IIIC. Mini Disks, 2004
    - Greenblatt, 1-Oct-04; cuid4361 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Canall, 22-Oct-04; cuid4362 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Nafisi, 3-Dec-04; cuid4363 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Pete Hamill, Undated; cuid4364 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Frazier, Undated; cuid4365 (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - Election, Undated; cuid4366 (Box 76, Folder 29)
    - Post Election, Undated; cuid4367 (Box 76, Folder 30)
    - Satrapi, Undated; cuid4368 (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - Undefined (Label "Rachel Cohen" has been crossed out), Undated; cuid4369 (Box 76, Folder 32)
  - Subseries IIID. VHS Tapes, 1990-2010; 76 VHS
    - Art and Optics, December 1, 2001 (Box 77, Vhs Tape 1, 37-4.0077, 37-4.0078, 37-4.0079, 37-4.0080, Vhs Tape 2, 37-4.0081, 37-4.0082, 37-4.0083, 37-4.0084, Vhs Tape 3, 37-4.0085, 37-4.0086, 37-4.0087, 37-4.0088, Vhs Tape 4, 37-4.0089, 37-4.0090, 37-4.0091, 37-4.0092, Vhs Tape 5, 37-4.0093, 37-4.0094, 37-4.0095, 37-4.0096, Vhs Tape 6, 37-4.0097, 37-4.0098, 37-4.0099, 37-4.0100, Vhs Tape 7, 37-4.0101, 37-4.0102, 37-4.0103, 37-4.0104)
      There are four copies of Tape 1 (37-4.0077 - 37-4.0080), four copies of Tape 2 (37-4.0081 - 37-4.0084), four copies of Tape 3 (37-4.0085 - 37-4.0088), four copies of Tape 4 (37-4.0089 - 37-4.0092), four copies of Tape 5 (37-4.0093 - 37-4.0096), four copies of Tape 6 (37-4.0097 - 37-4.0100), and four copies of Tape 7 ( 37-4.0101 - 37-4.0104).
    - Joel Meyerowitz: Images From Ground Zero, May 13, 2002 (Box 77, Vhs 37-4.0105, 37-4.0106, 37-4.0107)
    - Us vs. Them: Introduction and Panel 1: American Exceptionalism, October 23, 2004 (Box 77, Vhs 37-4.0108, 37-4.0109, 37-4.0110, 37-4.0111, 37-4.0112, 37-4.0113)
      6 copies of the same recording.
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 2: Constitutional Separation of Church and State, October 23, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0114, 37-4.0115, 37-4.0116, 37-4.0117, 37-4.0118, 37-4.0119, 37-4.0120)
      7 copies of the same recording.
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 3: Conversation with Weschler, Kushner and Vowell, October 23, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0121, 37-4.0122, 37-4.0123, 37-4.0124, 37-4.0125, 37-4.0126, 37-4.0127)
      Seven copies of the same recording.
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 4: Religious and Philosophical Vantages, October 23, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0128, 37-4.0129, 37-4.0130, 37-4.0131, 37-4.0132, 37-4.0133, 37-4.0134)
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 5: Scientific Vantages, October 23, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0135, 37-4.0136, 37-4.0137, 37-4.0138, 37-4.0139, 37-4.0140, 37-4.0141)
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 1: The Islamic Horizon, October 24, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0142, 37-4.0143, 37-4.0144, 37-4.0145, 37-4.0146, 37-4.0147)
    - Us vs. Them: Panel 2: Wider Perspectives, October 24, 2004 (Box 78, Vhs 37-4.0148, 37-4.0149, 37-4.0150, 37-4.0151, 37-4.0152, 37-4.0153)
    - Videoconference between NYU's Institute for the Humanities and Open Society Institute, February 2, 2000 (Box 77, Vhs 37-4.0154)
    - Light Shadow Therapy Institute: Vitaly Komar, Alex Melamid, William McClelland, Undated (Box 77, Vhs 37-4.0155)